影片中的“佐伦”及所有人物角色均属虚构
并非影射任何公司或人物
还以为你永远回不来了
Thought you'd never get back.
那儿极度挤拥
Well, there was a heck of a crowd on the piece.
原来如此
So I see.
- 任务完成了？- 最好的鱼子酱
- Mission accomplished? - Best beluga…
伏特加 要轻摇匀的还有…
vodka, rather shaken, and…
- 一块微型晶片 - 真棒
- one microchip. - Good.
我通知M
I'll make a signal to M.
可否做我的乖女孩 让它自动行驶？
Be a good girl, would you, and put her on automatic?
我们可以喝杯酒
And we could do with a couple of glasses.
酒杯在头顶的架子上
They're in the overhead rack.
邦德中校！
Oh, Commander Bond.
叫我詹姆斯吧 到阿拉斯加要五天的时间
Call me James. It's five days to Alaska.
《007系列之雷霆杀机》
开始 前进！
Walk. March!
谢天谢地 你终于回来了
Thank goodness you're here, James.
钱班霓 很漂亮呢
That's very nice, Moneypenny.
上班时穿这样 不是太隆重吗？
Don't you think it's a little over the top for the office?
我整个上午都在找你 你在做什么？
I've tried to reach you all morning. What have you been up to?
亲爱的 休息和消遣
Well, rest and recreation, my darling.
从西伯利亚回来的旅程使我累透了
The trip back from Siberia took a lot out of me.
你对工作的全力投入是最值得表扬的
Your dedication when you're on the job is most commendable, James.
钱班霓小姐 别说客套话了
Omit the customary pleasantries, Miss Moneypenny.
我们没有时问
We're pressed for time.
稍后再跟你说 钱班霓
I'll fill you in later, Moneypenny.
- 早安 两位 - 邦德 你好
- Minister. Good morning, sir. - Commander.
Q 是新宠物吗？
A new pet, Q?
如果你看过我部门发出的备忘录
If, 007, you'd ever bother to read any memos from my department…
你定会知道这是一个精密监测仪器的样本
you would realize this is a prototype of a sophisticated surveillance machine.
你可以开始简报
Now that we're all here, you can get on with the briefing, Q.
非常好
Very good, sir.
各位…
Gentlemen…
硅集成电路…
a silicon integrated circuit.
是所有现代电脑的重要部分
The essential part of all modern computers.
不要教学 Q 我们都知道微型晶片的实用性
No lecture, Q. We're all aware of the usefulness of the microchip.
直到最近
Well, now, until recently…
微型晶片被发现容易受到…
all microchips were susceptible to damage…
核爆引致的磁脉冲所破坏
from the intense magnetic pulse of a nuclear explosion.
- 磁脉冲？- 没错
- Magnetic pulse? - Yes, Minister.
若在英国上空的外太空爆炸 所有镶有微型晶片的东西
One burst in outer space over the U.K., and everything with a microchip…
从烤面包机到最精密的电脑
from the modern toaster to the most sophisticated computers…
和我们的防卫系统等都会变得没用
and our defense systems would be rendered absolutely useless.
我们会被苏俄弄至瘫痪
We'd be paralyzed at the Russian's mercy.
所以我们其中一个私人承办商就发明了这个
That is why one of our private defense contractors came up with this…
一块完全不受磁脉冲破坏的晶片
a chip totally impervious to magnetic pulse damage.
若我把它放在微型比较仪上
Now, if I place it on the microcomparator…
再跟邦德在西伯利亚
and compare it with the chip Commander Bond recovered…
003的身上所寻回的晶片比较…
from the body of 003 in Siberia…
当我把两个影像结合时…
when I bring the two images together…
它们完全相同
They're identical.
国安会一定有渠道取得了那研究公司的情报
The KGB must have a pipeline into that research company.
看来也是
It would appear so.
六个月前 该公司被一家英法联合公司收购
Six months ago, that company was acquired by an Anglo-French combine…
佐伦工业
Zorin Industries.
我想 已对工厂进行了安全检查？
I presume, sir, there has been a security check of the plant?
已大规模地检查 但找不到线索
And a very extensive one, but we have no leads.
佐伦本人呢？
What about Zorin himself?
麦斯佐伦？不可能 他是法国首席工业家
Max Zorin? Lmpossible. He's a leading French industrialist…
绝对反共产主义 认识不少有影响力的政府官员
a staunch anticommunist with influential friends in the government.
对 不过 部长…
Yes, but with due respect, Minister…
消息的确是在佐伦收购那公司之后给泄露了
the leak did occur after Zorin bought the company.
所以我已经展开调查
Precisely why I've already initiated an investigation.
好吧 那我们得谨慎一点
All right, but for heaven's sake, let's be discreet about it.
当然了 部长
But of course, Minister.
给你35分钟梳洗装扮正式点
You have exactly 35 minutes to get properly dressed, 007.
快些 弗卢克
Come on, Fluke…
快移动你的…
move your a…
谁是第一？那匹灰色的？
Who's number one… the gray with him?
那是佐伦的马 珀加索斯
That's Pegasus, Zorin's horse.
那个拿着手杖的就是佐伦？
With the cane… is that Max Zorin?
对 生于德勒斯登
Yes. Born in Dresden…
60年代从东德逃走
fled from East Germany in the '60s…
持法国护照 至少会讲五种语言 而且没口音
French passport, speaks at least five languages with no accent…
是当今城中的谈论焦点 而且位高权重
now the talk of the city and the boss.
- 跑快些！- 又是老掉牙的暴发致富的故事
- Come on, Fluke! - The old rags-to-riches story.
石油汽油贸易为他带来第一批财富
Made his first fortune in oil and gas trading…
现在轮到电子和高科技工业
now a second in electronics and high-tech.
那个在他身边、鼓着帽子…
Who's that with him, under the hat…
穿红裙子的是他女朋友吗？
with the red dress… girlfriend?
我们对她所知不多
We're not sure about her.
她是美国人 从不离开他半步
American… she's never far from him.
名字叫美黛
Name's May Day.
她懂得为场合穿衣
And dressed for the occasion.
弗卢克 加把劲！
Come on, Fluke, get a wiggle on!
第一名是一号、第二名是二号 第三名是五号
First, number one; second, number two; and third, number five.
第一名 一号珀加索斯
First number one, Pegasus.
第二名 二号弗卢克 第三名 五号美洲狮女
Second number two, Fluke;and third number five, Cooper Girl.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
我当了多年练马师
In all my years as a trainer…
从没见过在最后冲刺时跑得这样快的马
I've never seen a horse run such a fast last furlough.
我们部门的戈弗雷帝毕
Sir Godfrey Tibbett, our department.
- 恭喜你 - 谢谢
- Many congratulations. - Thank you.
佐伦很幸运
Lucky man, Zorin.
- 不尽是幸运 - 贿赂？
- Could be more than luck, admiral. - Fixed?
你的估计跟我的一样
Your guess is as good as mine.
法国赛马会已雇用我一位侦探朋友…
The French Jockey Club have hired a detective friend of mine…
奥伯格林去追查
Aubergine, to look into it.
哗！
Whoa!
放松点！
Easy, Pegasus!
冷静下来…
Calm down. Calm down.
轻松点…
Easy. Steady, steady.
- 她一定吃了很多维他命 - 冷静些
- She must take a lot of vitamins. - Steady, baby.
- 也许珀加索斯也一样 - 没事的
- Perhaps Pegasus does too. - Easy, baby.
我应该跟你的侦探朋友见面
I think I should meet with this detective friend of yours, Sir Godfrey.
对 也许会有些有趣的资料
Yes. Might have some interesting information for us.
- 那你准备一下 - 没问题
- Set it up, Tibbett. - Right you are, Admiral.
钱班霓 可以帮我拿彩金吗？
Moneypenny, be a darling, would you, and collect that for me?
回去时我请你吃晚饭 珀加索斯
I'll buy you dinner when we get back.
1975年的博林根
Bollinger, '75.
似乎你也是专家
I see you are a connoisseur, Monsieur Bond.
也是一个极好的选择
Another excellent choice.
很高兴你同意 因为付帐的是你
I am pleased you approve, since you're paying the bill.
干杯
Cheers.
你指S局没有佐伦…
You were saying that the S?iret has no information about Zorin…
在逃离东德前的资料？
before he came over from East Germany?
我经过线人亲自看过他的档案
Through a personal connection, I saw his dossier myself…
不过即使S局的那些档案有时也会有所缺漏吧？
but even S?iret?records are sometimes incomplete, eh?
迷人的多米尼克…
The fabulous Dominique…
和漂亮的凤蝶
and the enchanted papillons.
我们或许应把这些蝴蝶拨入收藏品中 不好吗？
Perhaps we should add this butterfly to our collection, no?
为何佐伦的马…
Tell me, why do Zorin's horses…
能击败其他优良血统的马匹？
beat others with far superior bloodlines?
- 这是一个谜 - 他有使用药物吗？
- This is a mystery. - Could he be using drugs?
测试结果显示没有
Nothing showed up on the tests.
本月稍后时间…
Later this month…
佐伦会在他位于巴黎附近的马场举行年度展销会
Zorin will hold his annual sales at a stud near Paris.
保全非常严密
Security is formidable…
不过谜团的答案就在那里
but the key to this mystery is there.
而我…
And I…
奥伯格林很想找它出来
Achilles Aubergine, intend to find it.
他的汤里有苍蝇
There's a fly in his soup.
- 追那降落伞 - 别说英语
- Follow that parachute! - Is in English.
出来
Out.
我的车！
My car!
恭喜你
Congratulations.
怎样？
So?
我不是说过这行动要谨慎地进行吗？
May I remind you that this operation was to be conducted discreetly?
你造成六百万法郎的破坏
All it took was six million francs in damage…
还有违反部分拿破仑法典的罚款
and penalties for violating most of the Napoleonic Code.
在那情形下 我觉得去识别出暗杀者是很重要的事
Under the circumstances, sir, I felt it important to identify the assassin.
你在奥伯格林不幸过杀时知道了什么？
What did you learn from Aubergine before his untimely demise?
佐伦将在附近的一个马场售卖他的纯种马
Well, only that Zorin is having a thoroughbred sale at his stud nearby.
我应该要去
I think I should be there.
戈弗雷爵士 你可以帮我吗？
Can you help me with that, Sir Godfrey?
安排获邀请应该没问题
It may be possible to arrange an invitation.
虽然通知时间短促
It's a bit short notice…
但应该是没问题的
but I might just be able to squeeze you in, Bond.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
戈弗雷爵士 请戴上帽子
Sir Godfrey, your hat.
圣约翰史密尔先生？
Mr. St. John Smythe?
是圣约翰史迈尔
St. John Smythe, my dear.
史迈尔先生 我是安全部主管斯卡彭
Monsieur Smythe, my name is Scarpine, head of security.
- 你好 - 已为你在城堡里准备了房间
- How do you do? - We have a room for you at the chateau.
那太好了
Oh, splendid.
是了 主马厩已开始进行预展
By the way, the preview is already in progress at the main stables.
- 是那儿吗？- 不 那些是仆人的住处
- Is that it? - No, those are the servants' quarters.
马厩在那一边
The stable's over here.
让我带你去
Let me escort you there.
- 是马匹的目录 - 谢谢你
- Catalogue of the sales. - Thank you.
那匹幼驹伊萨古斯 它在吗？
Tell me, the lthacus colt… is it here?
- 你指珀加索斯的嫡亲弟弟？- 对
- You mean the full brother of Pegasus? - Yes.
它是这次展销中心最出众的马
He's the outstanding horse of the sales.
它会最后迟出来 我们预期它以超过三百万卖出
He'll be shown last. We expect him to fetch over $3 million.
听起来颇合理
Sounds quite reasonable.
若你有什么需要就找我
If you're in need of any further assistance, please call me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
珀加索斯 镇静点…
Steady! Steady, Pegasus, steady.
牢牢绑着它
Keep him on a tight rein!
第三十号 我们非常荣幸
Lot number 30. We are now very proud…
为你介绍珀加索斯的嫡亲弟弟
to present the full brother to Pegasus.
这匹一岁大的幼驹…
This yearling foal is born…
佐伦先生有事被耽搁了
Monsieur Zorin has been unavoidably detained.
他很希望见你 他想在稍后…
He's anxious to meet you, hopes to do so at the reception…
城堡花园的欢迎会中跟你见面
at the chateau gardens later.
我期待着 帝毕 请你别到处逛
I look forward to it. There you are, Tibbett. I wish you wouldn't wander off.
- 那才是个友好仆人 - 对不起
- There's a good chap. - I'm sorry, sir.
你的司机可以在仆人的住处过夜
Your driver may stay the night in the servants' quarters.
相信对他来说已足够了
Why, I'm sure that'll be more than adequate for him.
对吗 帝毕？
What do you say, Tibbett?
- 欢迎你 我是珍妮弗斯 - 当然了
- Welcome, sir. I'm Jenny Flex. - Of course you are.
- 我叫服务生来 - 不用了
- I'll call a porter. - Oh, that won't be necessary.
我的下人会搬的了
My man'll take care of it.
- 让我带你到房间去 - 麻烦你
- Let me show you to your room. - Thank you.
准备好就上来吧
When you're ready, Tibbett.
我猜你花许多时间骑马
Well, my dear, I take it you spend quite a lot of time in the saddle.
- 对 我喜欢早上骑马 - 我也是早起床的人
- Yes, I love an early-morning ride. - I'm an early riser myself.
快上来 帝毕 别再喘气体
Come along, Tibbett. Stop wheezing.
别站着喘气 帝毕 把衣物拿出来
Well, don't stand there panting, Tibbett. Start the unpacking.
- 让我帮你 - 谢谢你
- Here, let me help you. - Yes, sir. Oh, thank you, sir.
- 欢迎会六点开始 - 谢谢你
- The reception is at 6:00. - Thank you, my dear.
听到弗斯小姐说吧 六点有欢迎会
Well, Tibbett, you heard what Miss Flex said: There's a reception at 6:00.
- 是的 - 我要穿白色外衣 黑领带
- Yes, sir. - So, white jacket and black tie.
是的
Yes, sir.
- 可以的话 要一件干净衬衫 - 是的
- And, if possible, a clean shirt. - Yes, sir.
我的天 看看我的衣服
Oh, my Lord, Tibbett. Look at the state of my clothes.
- 你怎样放置我的行李的？- 对不起
- How on earth do you pack my bags? - Sorry, sir.
福勒先生向他的练马师说 他会用一百万号竞投伊萨古斯
Mr. Fowler has told his trainer he'll go to a million for the lthacus colt.
好极 听到史迈尔什么说吗？
Good. Anything from St. John Smythe?
他没说关于买马的事 幸好我不是他的司机
Nothing about the sales, sir, but I'd hate to be his valet.
你下次不要这么做了
You're certainly going to have to buck up your ideas.
对不起
I'm sorry, sir.
别这样卑躬屈膝
Don't be so damned obsequious.
天 这些鞋子怎么了？
Oh, my Lord. What the devil's wrong with these shoes?
像给满是油的抹布擦过似的
They look as if they were wiped over with an oily rag.
- 很对不起 - 一点都没错
- Terribly sorry, sir. - You blasted well should be.
你是否不想再做我的仆…
I don't know how long you expect to remain in my employ…
做得很好
Well done, my good man.
即使我们单独时都要继续做戏？
Do we have to keep this up when we're alone?
完美的乔装是必不可少的
Well, a successful cover becomes almost second nature.
珀加索斯不见了是怎么回事？
What's all this business about Pegasus disappearing?
这分钟它还在马厩里 下分钟却突然消失了
One minute he's in his stall, the next… neither hide nor hair of him.
- 我们要去查一查 - 不要太担心这事
- We should look into it. - Don't concern yourself with that.
那是我在珀加索斯马厩里见到的男人
There's the man I saw at the Pegasus stable.
- 另一个有钱马主？- 谁知道？
- Another wealthy owner? - Who knows?
不过最好密切监视她
But she'd certainly bear closer inspection.
- 我们有任务在身的 - 戈弗雷爵士
- We're on a mission. - Sir Godfrey…
我已准备为进行任务而牺牲自己
on a mission, I am expected to sacrifice myself.
很好的派对
Lovely party.
史迈尔先生 喜欢这派对吗？
Enjoying our little party, Monsieur St. John Smythe?
当然了 我叫史迈尔
Oh, immensely. St. John Smythe.
似乎你将有不错的收获
Looks like you'll have a good turnout for the sale tomorrow, doesn't it?
失陪
Excuse me.
她是塞顿小姐
May I introduce Miss Sutton?
- 法罗酋长 - 你好吗？
- Sheik Farouq. - How do you do?
（祈付塞顿五百万）
我很荣幸
And it's a great pleasure.
- 欢迎 - 佐伦先生
- Welcome. - Mr. Zorin.
「主攻计划」已准备好？
Main Strike all set?
还有 在22日之后
Well, no. After the 22nd.
- 谢谢你 - 请随便
- Merci. - Enjoy yourself.
你在找什么吗？
You were looking for something?
对 我想到酒吧去
Yes, I was looking for the bar.
来 我带你去
Come, I will show you.
是了 是 圣约翰史迈尔
By the way, the name is St. John Smythe.
詹姆斯圣约翰史迈尔
James St. John Smythe.
卡尔莫勒博士 多多指教
Dr. Carl Mortner, at your service.
- 博士 - 你好 午安 科尼先生
- Hiya, Doc. - Good afternoon, Mr. Conley.
科尼先生 史迈尔先生
Mr. Conley, Mr. Smythe.
- 鲍伯科尼 - 你是练马师吗？
- Bob Conley. - Are you a trainer?
我连骑马也不会 我从事石油业的
Horses? Hell, I can't even ride. I'm in the oil business.
德克萨斯？
Oh. Texas?
旧金山 我处理佐伦先生那边的石油事业
Frisco. I handle Mr. Zorin's oil interests there.
恕我失陪
Would you excuse us?
来 我带你看些有趣的东西
Come on, honey. I'll show you something really interesting.
你是医学博士吗？
Tell me, are you a doctor of medicine?
我是佐伦先生的马匹繁殖顾问
I am Mr. Zorin's breeding consultant.
是吗？那么你可以解答我的疑问了
Oh, really? Then you can let me in to a little secret.
你如何能成功繁殖…
How is it you succeed with breeding bloodlines…
其他专家认为是低劣品种的马匹？
that other experts consider inferior?
选择性繁殖的确重要
Selective breeding is important, ja…
但更重要的却是训练和欲望 对吗？
but more important is conditioning and a desire, ja?
你指对人还是对马？
Are you talking about people or horses?
我的原理同样应用到人类身上
My principles apply equally to human beings.
史迈尔先生 让我自我介绍
Mr. St. John Smythe, allow me to introduce myself.
佐伦先生 幸会
Mr. Zorin, it's a great pleasure.
卡尔 有一个马夫请你到马厩去
Carl, one of the grooms asked if you'd go to the stables.
好的 失陪
Of course. You will excuse me?
恭喜你 佐伦先生 你的马厩很壮丽
I must congratulate you, Mr. Zorin. Your stables are magnificent.
那是16世纪时由一位公爵建造的 他深信自己会化身为马匹
Built in the 16th century by a duke who believed he'd reincarnate as a horse.
你很久前已对纯种马有兴趣？
Have you been interested in thoroughbreds long?
不 其实是我一位古怪的姨母死了
Oh, no. As a matter of fact, I had a rather dotty old aunt die…
留给我一些马厩 所以我才想…
and leave me some stables, so I thought it might be rather fun…
繁殖和饲养马匹
to breed and raise horses.
我猜你爱骑马
I take it you ride.
那是我最开心的时候
I'm happiest in the saddle.
果然是爱好运动的人
A fellow sportsman.
钓鱼呢？
What about fishing?
假蝇钩鱼
Fly casting.
我要去招呼其他宾客
I'm neglecting my other guests.
请随便 你会发觉她们会是刺激的伴儿
Enjoy yourself. You'll find the young ladies stimulating company.
相信她们是
I'm sure they are.
你好 为何不跟其他人一起？
Hello. I thought you might like to join the party.
是了 我叫做圣约翰史迈尔
By the way, the name is James St. John Smythe.
我是英国人
I'm English.
- 真猜不到 - 是吗？
- I never would have guessed. - Really?
你是买家还是卖家？
Well, are you buying or selling?
- 卖家？- 马匹
- Selling? - Horses.
我对马匹没有兴趣
No, I'm not interested in horses.
那你不该到这里来 是吗？
Well, you came to the wrong place, didn't you?
美黛
May Day…
别让他接近她
get her away from him.
我确定曾在什么地方见过他的
I'm sure I've seen him somewhere before.
请警卫盯紧他
Have security keep a good eye on him.
你还没说你来自什么地方 你是…
By the way, you didn't say what part of the States you come from, Miss…
我还没说
No, I didn't.
我猜你经常到处去旅行
I suppose you travel a lot.
你的直升机二十分钟后离开
Your helicopter leaves in 20 minutes.
你今晚不会留下吗？
Oh, does that mean you're not staying the night?
我还想跟你一起共度今宵
I was hoping we'd spend the evening together.
现在只剩我一人
Now I shall be all alone.
我才不相信
I doubt that.
- 让我送你上直升机 - 不用了
- Well, let me walk you to the chopper. - That won't be necessary.
有人会照顾你的
Someone will take care of you.
你会亲自确定的吧？
Oh, you'll see to that personally, will you?
你在找这个吗？
Are you looking for this?
这下去的好方法真不错
Quite a letdown.
- 史迈尔怎么样？- 像婴儿般酣睡
- St. John Smythe? - Sleeping like a baby.
是这个了
Oh, that's it.
来…
There. There we are.
别动
Hold on.
真有趣 它动过手术
It's interesting. He's had surgery.
手术？
Surgery…
所以佐伦才会赢
that is how Zorin won the race.
莫勒博士将这样的微型晶片植入珀加索斯体内
The good Herr Doktor Mortner implanted one of these microchips into Pegasus.
看 这些微型晶片…
You see, these microchips…
能够控制注射到马匹身体里…
are programmed to control an injection…
多余的类固醇
of additional natural horse steroids…
使马匹在比赛中不会感到乏力
which will overcome fatigue during the race.
怎样运作？
How?
液体由这小针筒注射
Well, the injection itself, with that small needle, is triggered…
它由遥控发射器操控
by a remote control transmitter…
外型细小 能藏在骑师的马鞭尖端…
small enough to fit into the tip of a jockey's whip…
或者笞条的尖瑞
or a cane.
关灯
The lights!
佐伦把这么多的微型晶片囤积起来
There's a world surplus of microchips, and Zorin is hoarding them.
- 抱歉没帮上什么忙 - 放心 已处理好了
- I'm afraid I wasn't much help. - Don't worry, it's all wrapped up.
提高警觉 保持平街
Keep your guard up higher, and retain your balance.
我抓住你了
Got you now.
- 现在怎办？- 我们最好回去
- What now? - We better get back.
录音带五分钟前已播放完 晚安
The tape ran out five minutes ago. Good night.
我叫你别骚扰我们
I told you not to disturb us.
不过此事非常重要
But it's very important.
仓库曾被人进入
There's been intruders in the warehouse.
叫警卫全面戒备
Put security on full alert.
看看史迈尔先生在哪里
Let's see where Mr. St. John Smythe is.
他是艾菲尔铁塔的那个男子
He was the man at the Eiffel Tower.
- 我们必须找他出来 - 我去更衣
- We must find him. - I'll get dressed.
美黛 你去了哪里？
May Day, where have you been?
我一直在等你
I've been waiting for you…
「亲自照顾我」
to take care of me personally.
我知道你是个不多言的女人
I see you're a woman of very few words.
有什么需要说？
What's there to say?
- 有什么不见了吗？- 没有
- Is everything here? - Ja, ja.
除了这个
Except this.
放在不当的位置
It is in the wrong place.
明早第一件事就是叫史迈尔到我书房
Bring St. John Smythe to my study first thing in the morning.
- 早安 - 早安
- Good morning. - Good morning.
我知道你想见我
I understand you wish to see me.
- 睡的好吗？- 有一点失眠
- You slept well? - A little restless…
但我最终也能入睡
but I got off eventually.
我的电脑上有一个幼驹索引
I have the progeny index on the computer.
当中有一个纯种马血统的汇编
That's a compilation of thoroughbred bloodlines.
或许能帮你在下午拣选你要买的马匹
It might be helpful to you in selecting your purchase this afternoon.
你应该需要一匹种马…
As I see it, you need a stallion…
来繁殖
for breeding.
也颇合理
A stallion sounds right to me.
我发觉电脑是不可缺少的
I find a computer indispensable.
我有一匹种马
I have a stallion…
是那匹马的后代
descended from that horse there.
米斯特
Misty.
（要求确认身分 自称英国人 圣约翰史迈尔）
电脑显示了我们有数匹马或许是你有兴趣的
According to the computer, we have several horse that might interest you.
好极
Splendid.
（英国情报员詹姆斯邦德 极度危险人物）
你注重体力还是速度？
Would you be interested primarily in stamina or speed?
两方面都有就最理想
Well, a little of both would be ideal.
（职业杀手）
我想我有一匹合适你的马
I think I have just the horse for you.
我要去骑马了
It's time for my morning ride.
不如你去试试策骑它？
Why don't you try him out?
好主意
Sounds a very good idea.
- 我先去更衣 - 好极了
- I shall get into some riding clothes. - Good.
那半小时后见 斯卡彭会来接你
Half an hour then? Scarpine will collect you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
帝毕 进城里 叫M追查这张支票
Tibbett, get into town. Call M and ask him to put a trace on this check.
快去 若我们被侍卫认出 我们就得尽快离开
Be as quick as you can. If those guards identify us, we'll have to move fast.
若他们问我去哪里 我怎回答？
What shall I say if they ask where I'm going?
你说要去洗车
You have to get the car washed.
我要到城里去洗车
Just going to town to get the car washed.
你可以骑了 史迈尔先生
Your mount, Mr. St. John Smythe.
果然是骏马
A beautiful beast.
充满生气 它叫什么名字？
A little spirited. What's his name?
地狱
Inferno.
- 是你的朋友吗？- 是练习骑师
- Friends of yours? - Exercise boys.
一起跳是比较实际的训练
Jumping together is more realistic training.
坦白说 我喜欢越野赛多于障碍赛
Well, quite frankly, I prefer cross-country to steeplechase.
作为一个爱好运动的人 我向你作出这个提议
As one sportsman to another, I'll make you a proposition.
若你能完成这赛道 我免费把伊萨古斯送给你
You can have that lthacus colt gratis if you stay this course.
若我堕马呢？
And if I'm thrown?
那你就输了
Then you lose.
你让我并无选择
You leave me little choice.
好极 斯卡彭会示意开始
Splendid. Scarpine will start us.
镇定！
Steady!
继续走！
Keep going!
戈弗雷 我们…
Sir Godfrey, let's…
你输了 007
You lost, 007.
杀掉帝毕是错的做法
Killing Tibbett was a mistake.
我打算再犯一次这样的错
I'm about to make the same mistake twice.
英国当局知道我在此的 若我不报告 他们会报复
My department know I'm here. When I don't report, they'll retaliate.
若你是他们最佳的情报员
If you're the best they have…
他们会乐意掩饰你不能胜任的事
they'll more likely try to cover up your embarrassing incompetence.
别指望它
Don't count on it, Zorin.
你使我发笑
You amuse me, Mr. Bond.
我不觉得好笑
Oh, it's not mutual.
到另一边去
Other side.
开门
Open up.
早安 佐伦同志
Good morning, Comrade Zorin.
戈高将军 你好
General Gogol.
这次会议很冒险
This meeting is ill-advised.
是冒险但有需要 因为你不听从指示
A calculated risk, but necessary, since you refuse to answer your control.
有话直说 将军
Come to the point, General.
你不理会程序
You disregard procedure.
你在未得到同意前 就消灭007
You did not request approval before eliminating 007.
报复行动或会妨害计划的进行
Reprisals might jeopardize ongoing operations.
你妨害我的计划！
You jeopardize mine!
竟让英国人渗入西伯利亚研究中心
Letting the British penetrate the Siberian research center.
那令人遗憾
That was regrettable.
你的赛马活动引来不必要的注意
Your racing activities attract unnecessary attention…
但更讨厌的是你未得批准而进行商业投机活动
but more disturbing are your unauthorized commercial ventures…
我们绝不可以容忍
and we cannot tolerate that.
这件事已没关系 我已作新的联盟
The issue is irrelevant. I've made new associations.
我不再视自己为国安会情报员
I no longer consider myself a KGB agent.
你是由我们训练的 资金是我们提供的
We trained you, financed you…
没有我们你怎么样？
What would you be without us?
生物实验？
A biological experiment?
生理上的怪物？
A physiological freak?
够了！不要胡闹
Enough of this! Control yourselves!
你会回来的 同志
You will come back to us, Comrade.
没有人会逃离国安会
No one ever leaves the KGB.
各位 数百年来
Gentlemen, for centuries…
炼金术士尝试从贱金属中炼金
alchemists tried to make gold from base metals.
今天我们由硅制造出微晶片
Today, we make microchips from silicon…
硅是一般的沙但比黄金要好
which is common sand, but far better than gold.
数年来 我们都是互惠的伙伴
Now, for several years we've had a profitable partnership…
你们去制造而我就去找和传达…
you as manufacturers, while I acquired and passed on to you…
一些能增加你的竞争力和使你们成功的…
industrial information that made you competitive…
工业资料
successful.
我们正处于一个独特的位置
We are now in the unique position…
去组成一个国际企业联盟
to form an international cartel…
去控制不只是微型晶片的生产
to control not only production…
而且还有分配权
but distribution of these microchips.
但有一个障碍
There is one obstacle.
硅谷…
Silicon Valley…
在旧金山附近
near San Francisco.
超过250家工厂
Over 250 plants…
聘用数千个科学家和技师
employing thousands of scientists, technicians.
这儿是美国电子生产的心脏地区
This is the heartland of electronic production in the United States…
占了全世界…
which accounts for what… 80 percent?
微型晶片市场的八成
Of the world microchip market.
我提议不要让…
I propose to end…
硅谷继续这垄断局面
the domination of Silicon Valley…
而让我们来控制这市场
and leave us in control of that market.
你有什么计划？
What is it you propose?
主攻计划
Project Main Strike…
你们每人要给我一亿元
for which each of you will pay me $ 100 million.
一亿元？
A hundred million dollars?
还有我们净收入的一半？
Plus half our net income?
跟我签订专利的销售协议
Under an exclusive marketing agreement with me.
简直是荒谬的条款！
These are outrageous terms!
或者示范过后你会认同
Well, perhaps a demonstration would convince you.
- 我不想参予 谢谢你 - 随便你吧
- I want no part of it, thank you. - As you wish.
我们余下的讨论内容很秘密
The rest of our discussion must, of course, be confidential.
- 请你到外面等好吗？- 你想的话 没问题
- Would you wait outside? - If you'd like me to, yes.
不好意思 麻烦你
Excuse me. Thank you.
美黛
May Day…
会招呼你喝一杯
will provide you with a drink.
这边
This way.
还有谁想退出吗？
So, does anybody else want to drop out?
哇！
Wow.
真漂亮
What a view.
最适合杀人
To a kill.
一个柠檬？五块钱
A lemon? Okay. Five dollars.
我可以帮你吗？你要什么？
Can I help the next person? Can I help you, sir?
- 也许我可以帮你 - 想找些特别的东西？
- May I help the next person? - Looking for something special?
- 是的 软壳蟹 - 里面应该有一些的
- Yes. Soft-shell crabs. - I might have some in the back.
我很快回来
I'll be a few minutes.
中情局的李查克 很高兴跟007合作
Chuck Lee, CIA. It's a pleasure working with 007.
谢谢 佐伦怎么样？
Thanks. Now what about Zorin?
他在城里 如果你想 我可派人跟踪他
He's in town. I can have him tailed if you want.
还没需要
Not yet.
科尼是个地质学家
Conley is a geologist.
在东湾负责佐伦石油开垦的工程
Runs Zorin's oil reclamation project in the East Bay.
在此之前是开垦南非金矿的总工程师
Last job, chief engineer on a South African gold mine.
矿洞塌下引致二十矿工死亡 他匆忙离开
Left in a hurry after a cave-in killed 20 miners.
似乎是佐伦的人 那女人和那支票呢？
Sounds like Zorin's kind of man. What about the girl and the check?
美国有许多叫塞顿的女人
You know how many S. Suttons there are in the US?
我们正留意佐伦的帐户 不过那支票还没兑现
We're watching Zorin's account, but the check hasn't been cashed yet.
莫勒呢？
Mortner?
你可被他骗倒了
You got a real winner here.
他其实叫汉斯格罗伯
His name is actually Hans Glaub…
是研发类固醇的德国先锋
a German pioneer in the development of steroids.
即是跟马匹注射有关
That ties in with the horse injections.
二次大战时 他为集中营的孕妇
During World War II, he experimented with steroids on pregnant women…
注射类固醇作实验以提高胎儿的智力
in the concentration camps in an attempt to enhance intelligence.
- 有成功吗？- 几乎所有孕妇都流产
- With any success? - Virtually every mother aborted…
只有少数婴儿有高度的智商
although a handful of children were produced with phenomenal IQs.
有副作用 他们都是疯子
But there was a side effect. They were psychotics.
为何格罗伯没被战争罪行委员会审讯？
Why wasn't this Mortner… or Glaub… tried by the War Crimes Commission?
俄国人把他抓去 把他困在实验室内
The Russians grabbed him. Set him up in a laboratory.
他花了数年研究类固醇帮助俄国运动员
He spent several years developing steroids for their athletes…
然后在十五年前不见了踪影
then dropped out of sight about 15 years ago.
差不多是佐伦逃到西方的时候
About the same time Zorin came over to the West.
佐伦会是其中一个类固醇孩子吗？
Could Zorin be one of the steroid kids?
年龄绝对吻合 而且他也是疯子
He's definitely the right age, and he's certainly psychotic.
那么他的石油企业呢？
What about his oil operations?
- 奥鲁克先生 - 嗨
- Mr. O'Rourke. - Hi.
- 打扰你一下好吗？- 没问题
- Can you spare a minute? - Sure thing.
那石油厂看来很正派 但却为捕蟹渔民带来麻烦
The whole operation looks clean except for a problem with the crab fishermen.
奥鲁克是他们的代表
O'Rourke represents them.
早安 奥鲁克先生 他是我向你提及过的记者
Good morning, Mr. O'Rourke. Here's that reporter I told you about.
奥鲁克先生 听说你遇到麻烦
Mr. O'Rourke, I understand you have a problem.
佐伦的抽油站破坏了其中一个最好的捕蟹地
That Zorin oil-pumping station ruined one of the best crab patches in the bay.
- 蟹被吓走了？- 不 蟹没有走
- Scared them away? - No, they didn't go nowhere.
它们只是消失了
They just disappeared.
我想去看看那抽油站
I'd like to take a look at that oil-pumping station.
很难的 那里守卫森严
That'll be tough. It's very heavily guarded.
稍后要测试新设备
We'll be testing new equipment shortly.
提高警觉
Keep a sharp lookout.
- 别让任何人走近这码头 - 是的
- I don't want anyone near this dock. - Very good, sir.
- 第5至15号井已打开 - 油井的情况怎样？
- Wells 5 to 15 are open, sir. - What's the report from the wells?
闸阀已打开准备进水
Wells report valves open and ready to receive water.
好极 打开16至25号闸阀
Good. Open valves 16 to 25.
十号闸阀只能有一半容量
Valve 10 operating at half capacity, sir.
把主攻计划的闸阀程序的最新情况告诉我
Give me an update on valve procedure on the Main Strike program.
明早会有队员作实地检查
We'll have a field crew check it out in the morning.
打开26至30号闸阀
Valves to wells 26 to 30 open, sir.
加快进水程序百分之五十力量
Right. Activate pumping procedure, 50% power.
加强力量
Increase it.
到最大
Maximum.
防线的新密封装置还没完全测试好
The new seals in the line are not fully tested.
三天后就是主攻计划
Main Strike's in three days.
任何延误…
Any delays…
你都要负责
I hold you responsible.
是的
Yes, sir.
全力开动 慢慢来
Bring it up to full, slowly.
- 关闭 - 怎么了？
- Shut down! - What is it?
- 螺旋桨给轧住 - 快去修理！
- Propeller's jammed! - Fix it!
派人潜进水底
You there, get a man down there!
- 快去 - 快来帮忙
- Let's go. Move it. - Come on, you guys. Give me a hand.
- 关掉警报系统 - 知道
- Get the alarms turned off. - Yes, sir.
按那按钮
Hit that switch there.
快些！清理那个帮浦
Hurry up, goddamn it! Clear that pump.
我们绝不可延误
It's the last thing we wanted. We're behind schedule.
给我
Give it to me.
警卫！
Guard!
叫科尼恢复进水
Tell Conley to resume pumping.
这是你的
This is yours, I believe.
拆去雷管
Defuse it.
宝娜伊凡诺瓦
Pola lvanova.
詹姆斯邦德！到那海滩看看！
Check the beach area. Make it fast.
我们快离开
Let's get out of here.
真舒服
That feels wonderful.
我这个位置更舒服
Feels even better from where I'm sitting.
要热一点吗？
Would you like it hotter?
你仍没变
You haven't changed.
但你变了
Well, you have.
变得更可爱
You're even lovelier.
我与博索尔在伦敦那一晚…
That night in London when I was with the Bolshoi…
演技出众
Ah, what a performance.
当我们后来在更衣室时…
In my dressing room later…
你知道我是被委派引诱你的特务吗？
did you know I was an agent with orders to seduce you?
不然我为何送你三打红玫瑰？
Why do you think I sent you three dozen red roses?
你演技才出众
Now that was a performance.
真巧合 我们竟然在这种情形下碰上
Quite a coincidence… us running into one another like this.
- 把真相告诉我 - 别谈公事
- Come on. Tell me the truth. - Let's not talk shop.
不如播放一些…
Let's put on something more…
激励人心的音乐
inspirational.
好主意
Why not?
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
这些泡泡使我发痒…
The bubbles tickle my…
柴可夫斯基！
Tchaikovsky!
可以缓和两国关系
Detente can be beautiful.
现在不是讨论政治的时候
This is no time to be discussing politics.
什么事？
Yes, darling?
你知道吗？
You know something.
明天我就送你六打红玫瑰
Tomorrow I shall buy you six dozen red roses.
太好了 我很心急
How lovely, darling. I can't wait.
录音带呢
The tape.
硅谷行动绝不能延误
The Silicon Valley operation must not be delayed.
三天后就是主攻计划
Main Strike's in three days.
任何延误…
Any delays…
你都需要负责
I hold you responsible.
必须确保…
It's essential…
其余管道准时打开
the remaining pipelines are open on time.
（豪尔办公室）
我们的经济需要像佐伦先生那样的投资者
Our economy needs investors like Mr. Zorin.
加州非常欢迎他
California welcomes him with open arms.
- 可以引用你这句话吗？- 当然可以
- May I quote you on that, Mr. Howe? - Certainly.
还有什么要我告诉伦敦经济时报吗？
Is there anything else I can tell the London Financial Times?
我的读者或想知道…
Yes. My readers may like to know…
为何佐伦把海水抽进到他的管子里…
why Zorin is pumping seawater into his pipeline…
而不是把石油抽出？
instead of pumping oil out?
海水是用以测试管道会否破损…
Seawater is used to test the integrity of the pipeline…
若管子出现裂缝 它比石油安全得多
it's a lot safer than oil… just in case there are any leaks.
这个我可不知道
L… I didn't know that.
- 谢谢你 豪尔先生 - 别客气
- Thank you, Mr. Howe. - Certainly.
- 访问到此为止 - 请从这边走
- That about wraps it up. - Would you come this way, please?
若再需要任何资料 请找我 阁下是…
If you'd like any further information, just call me, Mister…
詹姆斯史托 谢谢你
Stock. James Stock. Thank you, Mr. Howe.
- 豪尔先生 - 什么事？
- Mr. Howe. - Stacey, what do you want?
有些气孔测试想让你看看
I have some porosity tests I want to show you.
我要迟到了 只能给你两分钟
I'm running late. I can only spare a couple of minutes.
对不起
Sorry.
或者他知道你怎样想
Maybe he's after your mind.
晚安
Have a good night.
今晚气温稍低 华氏57度
We're looking for a low tonight of 57.
明天会升至华氏75度
High tomorrow, 75.
你们也可畅顺呼吸 空气污染指示说没有烟雾
And your lungs are in for a break. Air pollution control says no smog.
接下来有新闻简报
We're coming up on half past the hour and our news summary.
回来后送上更舒服的音乐 为通勤者解忧
And I'll be back with some more smooth sounds to soothe those commuter blues.
（圣安德烈斯湖水库）
慢慢走出来
Come out real slow.
又是佐伦另一个走狗 你是…
Just another Zorin stooge, Mister…
我不管你叫做什么
whatever your name was.
我叫詹姆斯史托 是伦敦经济时报的记者
Actually, it's James Stock, London Financial Times.
你可以告诉警方
You can… You can tell the police which.
你可告诉他们关于 佐伦给你五百万元报酬的事
Or you can tell them about the $5 million payoff you received from Zorin.
我见过那支票
I saw the check.
你切断了电话线
You cut the line.
退后！
Get back!
坐下来
Sit down.
里面装了什么？
What's this loaded with?
- 石盐 - 你现在才告诉我
- Rock salt. - Now you tell me.
那瓶子！
The vase!
拿着
Take this.
去死吧
Ah, hell.
对不起 爷爷
Sorry, Granddad.
等等我！
Hey, wait for me!
谢谢你
Thank you.
别客气
My pleasure.
恐怕所有皇帝的骑兵和手下都无法修补它
I'm afraid all the king's horses and all the king's men won't do much for that.
算了吧 那是爷爷的骨灰
It's all right. It was Granddad's ashes.
不过他很喜欢激战的
But he always loved a good fight.
我是史塔西塞顿
I'm Stacey Sutton.
你是记者？你叫做…
And you're a reporter? What was it?
- 詹姆斯史托 - 对
- Stock. James Stock. - Right.
我在为佐伦的报导搜集资料
I'm researching an article on Zorin.
所以我才借用朋友的名字 才得以获邀进城堡
That's why I used a friend's name to get an invitation to the chateau.
- 我可以告诉你佐伦的事 - 我很想听听
- I can tell you things about Zorin. - I'd like to hear them.
我要喂它 你饿吗？
I have to feed him. Are you hungry?
我们吃什么？猫饲料吗？
What are you serving, Whiskas?
冰箱只有少许吃剩的东西 我的厨艺很差劲
I only have a few leftovers in the fridge. I'm a pathetic cook.
- 让我帮你一把 - 你会煮饭？
- I'll lend a hand. - You can cook?
只会一点皮毛
I've been known to dabble.
完成了 蛋奶火腿蛋糕
Voila. Quiche des Cabinet.
似乎很不错 什么来的？
Sounds interesting. What is it?
煎蛋卷
An omelette.
继续说你爷爷的事吧
Now, you were telling me about your grandfather.
他把塞顿石油留给爸爸 爸就期望在我这个独女…
He left Sutton Oil to Dad, who expected me as the only child…
将来可继承他 所以我大学时念地质学
to take it over someday, so at college I studied geology.
- 然后呢？- 佐伦出现
- And then what happened? - Zorin.
他在一次虚构的代理权争战中接管了塞顿石油
He took over Sutton Oil in a rigged proxy fight.
我跟他上法庭争辩 我失去了一切…
I fought him in the courts. It's taken everything I had…
花尽所有现金 甚至连家具都卖掉
all the cash, the furniture, everything.
所以我当了州政府地质学家…
So I took this job as state geologist…
我只保住这房子和我的股份
and I've just managed to hold onto this house and then my shares.
那五百万就是你的股份？
That's what the $5 million were for, your shares?
那是我股份的十倍
Ten times more than they're worth.
他只想我闭嘴 停止诉讼
Just drop the lawsuit and shut my mouth.
我还没接受
I haven't accepted yet.
所以佐伦就派他的手下来帮你做决定
So Zorin sent along his gorillas to help you make up your mind.
他们已经帮我做了决定
They have.
我宁愿卖掉所有东西 住在帐篷也不会放弃
I'd sell everything and live in a tent before I'd give up.
味道真好
That was delicious.
你对那些家伙的身手…
And the way you handled those men…
那些…
Well, those…
粗野的人可会回来
baboons could come back.
希望不会
I hope not.
我去检查窗户…
I'll check the windows…
还有门户和再接回电话线
and the doors and… oh, reconnect the telephone.
那接合箱子在我卧房窗户外
The connecting box is outside my bedroom window.
我想我应该会找到的
I think I should be able to find that.
- 早安 - 早安
- Good morning. - Good morning.
太好了
Oh, I say.
有早餐送到 你的宠物怎么了？
Breakfast out of bed. What's wrong with your pets?
曾有轻微地震 它们对此很敏感的
We had an earth tremor. They're extremely sensitive to seismic activity.
看看地震中心的报告
Let's see what the earthquake center has on it.
只是轻微震动
Just a minor tremor.
里氏震级2.5级
Measured 2.5 on the Richter scale.
位置是…
Location…
很奇怪 震央在佐伦的油田附近
That's odd. The epicenter's near Zorin's oil field.
我昨天告诉豪尔 佐伦把海水抽进他的井
I told Howe yesterday that Zorin was pumping seawater into his wells.
- 两者有连系吗？- 海水？
- Is there a connection? - Seawater?
那些井在海沃德断层里
Those wells are in the Hayward Fault.
- 你肯是？- 我亲自查探的
- Are you sure? - I checked it myself.
那可非常危险
That's incredibly dangerous.
豪尔得马上制止佐伦
Howe has to stop Zorin now.
完全没道理！我没其他选择！
That is totally unreasonable. Now, look, you leave me no alternative.
- 什么事？- 他解雇我
- What happened? - I got fired.
- 他解…解雇我 - 冷静一点
- He fired… He fired me. - Now, calm down.
我们今晚跟我一位来自华盛顿的朋友见面
This evening we are going to meet a friend of mine from Washington.
或者…只是或者 他可以帮忙
Maybe… just maybe… he'll come up with a few answers.
我想知道佐伦的企图后 再进行下一步
Wish we were more specific about Zorin's intentions before I go to the top.
淹没断层会造成大地震的
Flooding a fault could cause a major earthquake.
但佐伦会有什么好处？
But what would Zorin have to gain?
佐伦曾在录音带上提及硅谷 那会受影响吗？
On the tape Zorin mentions Silicon Valley. Could that be affected?
影响不会太大 硅谷太远了
No, not severely. Silicon Valley's too far away.
若知道那包含了多少个井 我们就能更清楚现况
If we knew how many wells were involved, we might get a clearer picture.
资料可在市政厅找到
That information's available at city hall.
我仍有通行证
I still have my security pass.
- 那出发吧 - 让我上楼去拿
- Then let's go to city hall. - Let me go upstairs and get it.
我去请华盛顿加派协助
I'll contact Washington. Tell them we need more help out here.
别浪费时间 我们只有24小时
Don't waste time. According to the tape, there's only 24 hours.
- 晚安 杰克 - 晚安
- Good evening, Jack. - Evening, ma'am.
不会太久的
Won't be long.
（档案室）
「主攻计划」
"Main Strike."
我知道这个地方
I know that place.
圣安德烈斯断层旁有一个被弃置的银矿
That's an abandoned silver mine by the San Andreas Fault.
仍然安然活着
Alive and well, I see…
依旧在黑暗中把任务弄砸
and still bungling in the dark.
那你为何不给我点曙光？
Well, then why don't you enlighten me?
恐怕你不会明白
You're out of your depth.
而你 塞顿小姐
And you, Miss Sutton…
你应该接受我那比慷慨还好的条件
you should have accepted my more than generous offer.
- 你可以收回你的… - 别理他
- You can take your offer… - Don't bother.
他是变态的
He's a psychopath.
你俩联合起来了？
You two have joined forces?
那就易办了
That simplifies things.
他可能有武器
He's probably armed.
来
Come on.
- 佐伦先生 - 报警
- Mr. Zorin. - Call the police.
发生什么事？
What's going on?
通知警方有人非法闯进
Tell them there's been a break-in.
叫他们尽快赶来
Ask them to get here as soon as possible.
你被利用了 豪尔先生
You're being used, Mr. Howe.
打电话
Do it.
警察局
Police emergency.
你好 这里有人非法闯进
Hello. We've had a break-in here.
- 请说出位置在哪儿？- 市政厅 306号办公室
- Your location, sir? - City hall, office 306.
- 请马上来 - 我们立刻来
- Come at once. - Right away.
- 他们做了什么？- 你解雇她？
- What have they done? - You discharged her, huh?
所以她与她的同伙一起来杀你
So she and her accomplice came here to kill you.
然后就放火以掩饰罪行
Then they set fire to the office to conceal the crime…
不过他们却被困在升降机内
but they were trapped in the elevator…
葬身火海
and perished in the flames.
那即是说…
But that means…
我会…
I would have to be…
死
Dead.
这样不好吗？
That's rather neat, don't you think?
了不起 我佩服得无话可说
Brilliant. I'm almost speechless with admiration.
凭直觉而即兴做的…
Intuitive improvisation…
这是天才的秘密
it's the secret of genius.
莫勒博士会对他的产品感到自豪
Herr Doktor Mortner would be proud of his creation.
请
Please.
退后
Get back.
- 走！- 快离开
- Out. Out! - Come on. Let's go.
退后
Get back.
抓紧了
Hold tight.
快些
Come on, Stacey.
把手给我 伸过来
Give me your hand. Stretch!
伸过来！
Stretch!
别走开
Don't go away.
詹姆斯 别丢下我！
James, don't leave me!
救命！
Help me!
救救我！
我很快回来
I'll be right with you.
救命！
Help! Help!
- 是市政厅！- 我通知消防局
- It is the city hall! - I'll call the fire department!
尝试从梁的另一边
Try and come this side of the girder.
- 抓住它 - 我抓不到
- Catch this. - I can't reach it!
来 抓住它！
Come on, catch.
努力！
Now, swing!
来…
Come on.
乖 快到了
Good girl. You're nearly there.
来 来
Come on. Come on.
手伸出来
Stretch.
叫这电视采访队走开 好吗？
Get this TV crew out of here, will ya?
别挡我的路
Come on. Get out of my way.
让开！
Move back!
有人被困在市政厅内
All we know right now is that there are people trapped inside of city hall.
大火从顶层冒出
Flames coming out of the roof.
请你们让开
Back up, will you? Come on.
退后 让我们通过
Move back now. Let us through, goddamn it.
你们安全了
I got you, honey.
没事了
You're all right.
让她透一口气
Give her some air.
请别挡路
Coming through. Out of the way, please.
史塔西 安全了
Stacey, you're safe now.
让我过去
Let me through.
别挡路
Let me through, goddamn it!
- 我想跟你谈谈 - 队长
- Hey, buddy, I wanna talk to you. - Captain.
若你到豪尔先生的办公室 便会发现他已死去
If you can get through to Howe's office, you'll find him dead.
我们找到他 还找到这支枪 是你的吗？
We found him. And we found this gun. This yours?
- 是的 谢谢 - 转身
- Yes, thanks. - Turn around.
你可问问中情局的查克 他知道我是谁
Captain, if you check with Chuck Lee of the CIA, he'll tell you who I am.
- 我们在唐人街发现他的尸体 - 什么？
- We found his body in Chinatown. - What?
- 你已经被拘捕 - 等一下
- You're under arrest. - Wait a minute.
他是伦敦经济时报的詹姆斯史托
This is James Stock of the London Financial Times.
其实我是英国特工处的情报员
Well, actually, Captain, I'm with the British Secret Service.
我叫邦德 詹姆斯邦德
The name is Bond. James Bond.
- 是吗？- 真的？
- Is he? - Are you?
- 是 - 那我是狄克崔西 你已被捕
- Yes. - I'm Dick Tracy and you're under arrest.
上去
Get in here.
他去哪儿？梯子没有锁住的
Where's that guy goin'? That ladder's unlocked.
（危险 梯子未上锁时不要驾驶）
你真是英国特务？
Is that true what you said back there, about the British Secret Service?
是
I'm afraid it is.
我的真名是詹姆斯邦德 你得相信我的话
My real name is Bond. James Bond. You must take my word for it.
双手放这 放在方向盘上！方向盘！
Here, put your hand on this. The wheel, the wheel!
接过去 把脚踏在这位置
Take over. Put your foot on here.
你要去哪里？
James, where are you going?
所有单位 拦截被偷的消防车上的疑犯
To all units, intercept murder suspect in stolen fire truck.
他或许带有武器
He may be armed…
他是危险人物
and he's sure dangerous.
我们的挡泥板互相卡住了
Our fenders are locked.
我跟你说了 它们给卡住了
I told you, we're locked.
天啊！小心！
Oh, my God! Watch out!
拐弯！
Turn!
不是这边 是那边
Not this way, that way!
糟了！
Shit!
摇我回去！
Swing me back!
继续行驶
Drive on.
- 我想我可以追到他 - 去追！
- I think I can get him. - Go for it!
你疯了吗？
Hey, are you crazy?
他们就无法跟上来
That should keep them on the wrong track.
找谁？
Hello?
升起大桥？
Raise the bridge?
现在？
Right now?
知道
Yes, sir.
我要逮到他了
I got him. Oh, geez, I got him.
继续走！继续走！
Keep going! Keep going!
我的天！
Oh, my God!
让开！
Get out of the way!
我的天！
Jesus!
我的老天！
God! Oh, Mother!
糟了！
Shit!
走开！
Move it!
哈里斯？
Harris.
你休想升做警长
You can forget about that sergeant promotion.
你要赔偿那辆车 在每月的薪水里扣除一百块
You'll pay for that vehicle. One hundred bucks a month out of your paycheck.
醒来 我们到了
Wake up. We're there.
这个被弃置的矿场仍有许多活动进行
There's a lot of activity for an abandoned mine.
那卡车的炸药足够他们数个月使用
That truckload of explosives should last them for months.
这是下一年的供应量
Here comes next year's supply.
躺下
Get down.
- 哪儿发生火灾了？- 你的车子后面
- Where's the fire? - On your rear end.
帮帮忙
Give me a hand.
这是规例
It's the rules.
- 必须戴上安全帽 - 谢谢
- Hard hat area. - Thanks.
跟着指示
Follow the signs.
快点！你迟到了
Move it! You're late.
你们两个 过来
You two, come here.
帮一帮忙
Give us a hand.
放在那里
Okay, leave it there.
过去小屋喝杯咖啡
Get a coffee over in the hut.
二十分钟后回来
Come back in 20 minutes.
这是妇女解放运动 她们接收了工会
It's women's lib. They're taking over the Teamsters.
继续搬
Get this stuff movin'!
我们已迟了一小时
We're an hour late.
我该仔细看看那矿洞
I should take a closer look at that mine.
什么在阻止你？
What's stopping you?
你的主意真好
It's a good idea of yours.
可惜你没有一件合适的制服
Pity you couldn't find one that fits.
有车坐为什么要用走的？
Why walk when you can ride?
继续前进…
Keep it coming. Keep it coming.
- 你别动好吗？- 你知道我坐着什么吗？
- Will you keep still. - Do you know what I'm sitting on?
我尽量不去想
I'm trying not to think about it.
前面准备 带他们来 清除这些障碍物
Stand by forward. Bring the gang up here and clear these barriers away.
快来 我们时间不多
Come on. Let's go. We haven't got all day.
清除安全路障
Remove the safety barrier.
来 继续走
Come on. Move.
开起重机的 把那起重机吊架摆动到这边
On the crane. Swing the cradle over here.
拿起来…
Take it off. Take it off.
提起它 轻轻提起它
Bring it up. Bring it up, easy.
好…
Good, good.
- 找到什么吗？- 是的
- You found anything? - Yes.
我想我找到了
I think I have.
好…低一点
Good. Good. Lower.
把那些楔子紧紧地塞进去
Get those wedges in there tight.
塞进里面
Get 'em in.
（炸药）
圣安德烈斯湖就在我们上面
San Andreas Lake's right above us.
严重渗水 随时会淹水
Lots of seepage. Could flood any minute.
继续完成支撑顶部的工作
Finishing shoring up the roof.
我让拖车回来
I'll send the lug back.
尽快送些木材来
Bring up some timbers on the double!
他会杀死数百万人
He'll kill millions.
那些绿灯就是佐伦的油井
These green lights… they're Zorin's oil wells…
他就是用它们把海水打进海沃德断层内
the ones he's been using to pump seawater into the Hayward Fault.
这些湖下面的隧道有什么作用？
What are these tunnels for under these lakes?
它们直接通往圣安德烈斯断层的这部分
These lead straight into this section of the San Andreas fault.
佐伦只需要炸开这些湖的底部
You know, Zorin just has to blast through the bottom of these lakes…
就能淹没断层
to flood the fault.
- 并带来严重地震？- 对
- And create a double earthquake? - Yes.
除了…在我们脚下…
Except… except right beneath us…
那是地质学上的锁
is the key geological lock…
能立刻阻止断层移动
that keeps the faults from moving at once.
来吧
Hey, let's go.
所有那些炸药…
All those explosives…
能足够炸开那个锁吗？
would they be enough to break the lock?
当然
Of course.
若引爆炸药…
If they go off…
两个断层都会立刻移动
both faults move at once.
硅谷
Silicon Valley…
和硅谷的一切就会永远沉下去
and everything in it… submerged forever.
若在满潮爆炸 影响力将会更大
If it happened at the peak of the spring tide for maximum effect…
满潮在今早9时41分出现 还不到一小时！
That's today at 9:41. In less than an hour!
- 我们要去提醒大家 - 等等！
- We have to go and warn people. - Wait!
退后
Stand back.
跳
Jump.
捉住他
Get him.
叫他们回去工作
Get 'em back to work!
回去工作
Get back to work.
没事了 回去工作
Come on. It's all over. Get back to work.
是邦德
It's Bond.
关闭入口处 别让任何人出去
Close up the entrance. Nobody gets out.
停下来！
Hold it!
这里
In here.
来
Come on.
有见过任何人经过吗？
Did you pass anyone back there?
没有 没看到任何人
No. I saw no one.
现在应往哪边？
Now which way?
地图
The map.
那边是有通道的
There's a draft from up there.
- 一定是通风井 - 等等
- It must be a ventilation shaft. - Wait!
一定是通往断层的 是湖水
That must lead straight to the fault. The water from the lakes.
对 随时都会被淹没
Yes, it'll be flooding any moment.
来
Come on.
你俩去那边
You two, that way.
来 把手给我
Come on. Give me your hand.
是时候淹没断层
It's time to flood the fault.
但是美黛和我的手下…
But May Day and my men…
对 非常巧合
Yeah, a convenient coincidence.
但他们对你很忠心
Mr. Zorin, those men are loyal to you.
快点！
Hurry!
快找人来帮忙
Somebody get help, quick!
快逃！
Come on! Run for your life!
给我一些备用弹夹
Give me some spare clips.
继续爬！
Keep climbing!
Keep going!
好极了
Good.
并没延误
Right on schedule.
走吧
Let's go.
还以为那臭家伙爱我
And I thought that creep loved me!
不只你被他出卖
You're not the only one he double-crossed.
所有舷外阀都已锁上
All outboard valves fully locked, sir.
水位正在下降
The water level's dropping.
帮浦压力没问题
Pump pressure, good.
来吧 你现在无法再为他们做什么了
Come on. There's nothing you can do for them now.
升空离开！
Up and away!
硅谷
Silicon Valley.
太完美了
Perfect.
在这位置停下来
Hold position here.
只要几分钟
Only minutes more, Carl.
任何事也阻止不了
Nothing can stop it now.
史上最澎湃的…
The greatest cataclysm…
洪水
in history.
一切都因为自然灾祸
And all attributed to natural causes.
绝对是
Exactly.
赶快
We must hurry.
我要下去拆去那炸药雷管
I have to get down and defuse that detonator.
不 那计时器设置有陷阱的
You can't. The timer's been booby-trapped.
若你拨弄它 我们会被炸死
If you tamper with it, we're gonna blow up.
那我们须把它整个拿上来 但应怎做？
Then we have to bring the whole thing up. But how?
走上钻井架 我吊你下去
Get on the rig. I'll lower you down.
上去！
Get on!
继续
Keep going.
别停下
Come on. Come on.
停在那儿
Hold it there.
把它吊起来！
Take it up!
上来
Get on.
太重了 开始吧
It's too heavy. Go.
上去 混球！
Get on, damn it!
好了 开始！
Go.
继续！
Keep going!
可以了
That's it.
摆到卡车那边
Swing it over to the truck.
慢来
Easy.
慢慢来
Gently.
把它放下
All right, lower it.
提起它
Take her up.
不到一分钟它就要爆…
We've only seconds before this blows…
若真的爆炸的话 那火药桶也会给炸毁
and if it does, that powder keg goes with it.
来！
Come on!
手煞车松了
The hand brake slipped.
推！推！
Push! Push!
跳！
Jump!
- 我要控制那手煞车 - 跳下来！
- I have to hold the brake off. - Jump!
替我消灭佐伦！
Get Zorin for me!
美黛 跳下！
May Day, jump!
只剩下几秒
Only seconds to go.
美黛 跳！
May Day, jump!
美黛
May Day.
史塔西 伏下
Stacey, behind you! Get down!
拉她
Pull her.
拉她进去
Pull her in.
拉她到后面
Come on. Get in the back.
船头很重 他一是在停泊绳索上
The ship's nose is heavy. He must be on the mooring rope.
这个对他的伤害大于对我的伤害
This will hurt him more than me.
加大马力！
More… More power!
继续！
More. Do it!
全速前进！
Full throttle!
向右转 快些！
Right rudder. Do it!
- 停手！- 抓住她！
- Stop it! - Get her off!
- 抓住她！- 停手！
- Get her off! - Stop it!
- 你疯了吗？- 走开！
- Are you crazy? - Get away!
停手！
Stop!
去捉他
Go get him.
去！
Go!
跳下来！
Jump!
找地方站稳！
Get a foothold!
史塔西 把手给我
Stacey, give me your hand.
来
Come on.
躲到管子下
Get under the pipe.
待在这里
Okay, stay there.
小心！
Look out!
给我！
Give it to me!
史塔西 抓紧了！
Stacey, hold tight!
扔走它！
Get it out!
- 史塔西 你在吗？- 当然了
- Stacey, are you there? - You betcha.
上来
Here.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
没事
Yes. Yes.
当你需要计程车时 总是找不到一辆
There's never a cab when you want one.
给邦德同志的列宁勋章
The Order of Lenin for Comrade Bond.
历来首次颁授给苏联以外的市民
The first time ever awarded to a non-Soviet citizen.
我以为若硅谷被破坏
I would have expected the KGB to celebrate…
国安会是会庆祝的
if Silicon Valley had been destroyed.
相反 上将…
On the contrary, Admiral…
没有它 俄国会在哪儿做研究？
where would Russian research be without it?
邦德在吗？我想亲自感谢他
Is Commander Bond here? I'd like to thank him personally.
很可惜 他不见了
Sadly, he's missing.
我们会继续寻找…
We are continuing our search…
但作了最坏的打算
but must presume the worst.
或许这里涂多点肥皂 讨厌 我把肥皂弄掉了
Maybe a little soap there. Drat! I dropped the soap.
我去捡
I'll get it.
那不是肥皂
That is not the soap.
- 喂 - 爷爷找Q
- Hello? - Grandfather calling Q.
什么情况？
What's the position?
007仍活着
007 alive.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
他只不过在清理细微的地方
Just cleaning up a few details.
哦 詹姆斯
Oh, James.